I won't tell you again!
我不会跟你说第二遍!
Look, I'm not amused. Stop it!
听着, 这并不好玩, 停下！
(TWIG SNAPS)
Come on.
进来吧
(GRUNTING)
Make it keen.
要磨锋利
I want Sir Edward not to know the moment
when his head is parted from...
我期望爱德华爵士的头被砍下来的时候他还没有反应过来...
(SHOUTING)
- What's this!
- She was found within bowshot, Captain.
- 这是什么？  - 在弓箭射程之内找到的, 头儿
Idiots! Why don't you stop this ridiculous pantomime?
蠢人！你们就不能停止你们这荒谬的表演吗？
She spits fire, eh, Bloodaxe? Come here, girl.
她会吐火啊, 是不, Bloodaxe? 过来, 女孩
Get lost! Oh! Ow!
消失！哦, 噢！
- She wears gold, Bloodaxe.
- That hurt, you fool!
- 她戴着金首饰, Bloodaxe  - 弄疼我了, 你这蠢人！
You call Irongron a fool?
你管 Irongron 叫蠢人?
I'll have the marrow from your bones, my little chicken.
我要把你的骨髓碾出来, 我的小鸡
Where are you from?
你从哪里来的？
Look, just pack this up, will you? It's not funny.
行了, 收起这些吧, 行吗？这并不有趣
I happen to be a reporter, and I've got a big story...
我恰好是个记者, 我还有个大事件要...
Take her away, Bloodaxe. Throw her in the dungeon.
把他带走, Bloodaxe。扔到地牢里去
Why don't you take off that ridiculous gear
and go home to your butcher's shop?
你们为什么不脱掉你们那可笑的行头, 回到你们的肉铺去呢？
Let go! Look, I warn you.
放开！嘿, 我警告你
Any more of this and I'm going straight to the police.
再这样我就直接报警了啊
- Stay, Bloodaxe!
- Captain?
- 停下, Bloodaxe！  - 头儿？
Leave her.
放开她
That's better.
这还差不多
(SCOFFS) Now, if I could just use your telephone.
现在, 我能否用一下你们的电话
(MAN GROANING)
This is the dog that shot at you, Captain!
就是这条狗朝你射箭的, 头儿！
So you thought to kill Irongron, eh?
看来你是想杀 Irongron, 嗯？
Aye, and I would but for her. She drew my aim aside.
是, 要不是她我就成功了。她干扰了我
You treacherous dog!
你这奸诈的小狗！
- Did Sir Edward send you?
- No.
- 是爱德华爵士派你来的吗？  - 不是
- You lie!
- I speak the truth!
- 你撒谎！  - 我说的是事实！
- If not Sir Edward, who then?
- I don't understand. Where am I?
- 如果不是爱德华爵士, 那是谁？  - 我搞不懂了, 我在哪儿？
It was my Lady Eleanor.
是我家夫人 Eleanor
Ah, that narrow-hipped vixen.
啊, 那个小心眼的泼妇
Bloodaxe, tomorrow we dine at Wessex Castle.
Bloodaxe, 明天我们就到 Wessex 城堡去吃晚饭
Yes, Captain. And what of the prisoner?
好, 头儿！这个囚犯怎么处理？
Ere long we shall deal with him sharply.
稍后我们再来严厉处置他
(LAUGHING)
Sharply, eh? 'Tis richly put.
严厉地, 嗯？这词用得好吧
Aye. That'll be a fine jest, Captain Irongron.
啊, 那是个不错的词, Irongron 队长
I'm not one of your stuffy Norman nobles.
我可不是你们那些自以为是的诺曼贵族
I like a bit of rough fun.
我喜欢玩点野蛮趣味
'Tis true, Captain, you have a merry wit indeed!
这是真的, 头儿, 你真是个有头脑的人！
Look, please! Now you've had your laugh,
请, 听着！既然你们笑也笑了,
now, you know, just let's stop it and talk sensibly.
现在, 你看, 我们停下来认真地谈一谈
I mean, if it's any consolation to you,
you're scaring me out of my wits.
我是说, 如果你们觉得这些很好玩, 但我真的被吓破胆子了
- Perhaps the wench is crazed, Captain.
- Oh, come on. What is this place?
- 好像这个村姑被吓傻了, 头儿  - 噢, 得了, 这是什么地方？
You are in the castle of Irongron, my lady.
你在 Irongron 的城堡里, 我的夫人
Few uninvited guests come here,
and few that do leave alive.
很少有人不请自来, 更少人能活着离开
All right. If you insist on playing guessing games...
好吧, 如果你们非要玩这种猜谜游戏...
Now, it's not a village pageant.
It's too elaborate for that.
现在, 这不是一个村庄表演, 因为这太复杂了
A film set. No, no lights, no cameras.
电影拍摄现场。不, 没有灯, 也没有摄像机
Aye, the wench is crazed, right enough.
And pity, she's not un-comely.
是, 这村姑吓傻了, 肯定的。可惜了, 她本来还不难看
I've got it! It's one of those tourist places.
我知道了！这是一个旅游观光点
Uh, a medieval castle,
all restored to its original condition
喔, 一个中世纪城堡, 所有都恢复到原样
with jolly banquets and buxom serving wenches.
带着欢乐宴席, 活泼的女仆
That's it, isn't it?
就是这样, 对不对？
Mind you, I think you're overdoing the sordid realism a bit.
提醒一下,你们把脏乱这一点做得过头了
I mean, I know things were pretty grotty in the Middle Ages,
我是说, 我知道中世纪的时候很多东西是不怎么样
but, really, you might leave the tourists
a bit of glamorous illusion.
但, 真的, 你们应该给游客留下一个好的印象
I've never seen such a scurvy...
我从来没有见过这么无礼地...
For pity's sake, cease this babbling, girl!
天可怜见, 别叨叨了, 女孩儿！
BLOODAXE: Captain.
头儿
Ah, Linx. What of my weapons? Are they ready?
啊, Linx, 我的武器怎样了？准备好了吗？
Soon. But I have another weapon to show you.
快了。但我要给你展示另外一样武器
- For your leave, master, the prisoner?
- Aye, aye.
- 那就留给你了, 主人, 那个囚犯？  - 好, 好
- What is this?
- Eh?
- 这是什么？  - 嗯？
- Oh, just a girl taken in the forest.
- Girl?
- 哦, 只是一个女孩儿, 森林里面抓到的  - 女孩儿？
- You have two species on this planet?
- How say you?
- 你们这个星球有两个物种吗？  - 怎么说？
The girl is not of your kind, Irongron.
这个女孩跟你不是一个类别, Irongron
The hair is finer. The thorax of a different construction.
头发要好一些, 胸膛的结构也不太一样
Oh, hell's teeth, have you no girls beyond the stars?
哦, 可怜呐, 你们那星星上没有女孩儿？
- No women to do the lowly work?
- Ah, I understand.
- 没有人做一些低等的活儿？  - 啊, 我明白了
You have a primary and secondary reproductive cycle.
你们有一个高等和低等的生殖循环
It is an inefficient system. You should change it.
这个系统很没效率, 你们应该改掉它
You what?
你说什么？
In the Sontaran Military Academy,
在桑塔军事学院
we have hatchings of a million cadets at each muster parade.
我们每次集结时, 都生成上百万的士官生
Thus we can sustain enormous casualties on all battlefronts.
所以我们能承受那么多战线上的巨大伤亡
You cluck away like a broody old hen.
你们的方法好像多产的老母鸡啊
Wait! This cloth is machine-woven.
等一下, 这个衣服是机器造出来的
The girl is not of your time, Irongron.
这个女孩儿不是你们这个时代的, Irongron
Oh, curse the girl! Show me the...
啊, 该死的女孩！向我说明...
Who? What? How?
谁？ 什么？ 什么情况？
Sarah Jane Smith. Reporter.
莎拉-简-史密斯, 记者
In a machine. I did not understand it.
在一个机器里, 我搞不明白它
- What century?
- Twentieth.
- 哪个世纪？  - 二十
Your civilisation knows nothing
of time-dimensional technology. Explain.
你们的文明没有时间维度技术方面的知识。解释
I cannot. It is a machine that
belongs to someone called the Doctor.
我解释不了, 那个机器属于某个叫做博士的人
- Linx...
- Silence!
- Linx...  - 安静!
This is important. My mission is threatened.
这很重要, 我的任务有威胁了
Explain the Doctor.
解释一下“博士”
He is a scientist. He was at the research centre.
他是个科学家, 他当时在研究中心
He said he was very fond of delta particles.
他说他非常喜欢德尔塔粒子
Ah. Is he here?
啊, 他现在在这里吗？
Yes. Somewhere. I was hiding in the machine when he left.
是的, 在某个地方。他出来的时候我还躲在机器里
It becomes clear.
事情清楚了
Linx, what of the weapon?
Linx, 武器的事情怎样了？
Very well.
很好
It is here.
来了
Who are you? How do you come into my castle?
你是谁？你怎么到我的城堡里来的？
Well, speak fellow!
喂, 说话伙计！
Answer me or lose your head for insolence!
回答我, 否则你的头就没了, 无礼的家伙！
It cannot answer you.
It is just a suit of steel. It is empty.
它没法回答你。它只是一堆铁片, 里面是空的
But it walks!
但他能走路啊
It walks. And it fights, Irongron. Is it a good weapon?
它能走路, 还能战斗, Irongron。这个武器还不错吧？
Does it kill?
它能杀人吗？
It does nothing else and it cannot be killed.
它就会干这个, 而且还不会被杀
By heavens, Linx, can you make me more of these?
天啊, Linx, 你能给我多造几个这个吗？
If you wish.
只要你想要
With a few such soldiers as that, I could take the world!
只要有几个这样的士兵, 我能夺下整个世界！
When I have left this dull planet,
当我离开这个无趣的星球时
it would amuse me to think of it
under the rule of King Irongron.
想到它是在 Irongron 国王的统治之下, 还是会觉得有点意思的
Very well, provide me with all that I ask for
很好, 只要把我说的东西都提供过来
- and I can make many more of these.
- It's a bargain.
- 我就能找出更多这个来  - 说定了
By heavens, Linx, I never thought when I first saw you
老天, Linx, 我第一次看见你的时候, 我从没想到
that I should come to love you as a brother.
有一天我会像一个兄弟一样爱你
Now, show me how the iron man works.
现在, 给我展示一下铁人是怎么用的
Wait. The girl creature has gone.
等一下。那个女孩生物跑掉了
Oh, she'll not get far before one of my guards grabs her tail.
哦, 她跑不了多远就会被我的守卫给抓回来
Now, show me. Show me how it fights. Make it walk again.
来, 展示一下, 展示一下它是怎么战斗的, 让它再走起来
Sarah? Miss Smith. Come back!
莎拉？史密斯小姐。回来！
- Stay! Bloodaxe.
- Sire.
- 停下, Bloodaxe  - 大人
- Would you fight for your life, fellow?
- I'll fight any man, my lord.
- 你愿意为你的性命战斗吗, 伙计？  - 我愿意跟任何人打, 大人
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
- Then stand against Irongron's champion.
- Who is this?
- 那就来跟我的护卫打吧  - 这是谁？
You'll see some sport now, Bloodaxe. Here, fellow.
你也消遣一下, Bloodaxe。来吧, 伙计
Master, this is not fair combat
to pitch knight against bowman.
主人, 让骑士直接对战弓箭手是不公平
At this close range, his arrows'll
pierce the armour's weak points.
在这么近的距离下, 他的箭会刺穿盔甲的薄弱之处
- Take aim, fellow.
- I am that.
- 瞄准, 伙计  - 我瞄好了
Your freedom if you kill him. Stand back.
你能否自由就看你能否杀了他了。往后退
Your champion'll have more arrows
in his gizzard than a thistle has spikes.
你的护卫身上中的箭可要比刺猬的刺还多了
My lord, look! He still moves!
大人，快看！他还能动！
(MEN LAUGHING)
What fool...
哪个傻瓜...
Guard your back, my lord!
注意你后面，大人！
BLOODAXE: Captain!
头儿！
Psst!
噗斯
By heavens, Bloodaxe, 'tis like a tin tadpole.
老天，Bloodaxe，这家伙就像个蝌蚪似的
You cut off its head and yet it wriggles.
砍掉它的脑袋，它还能扭动
I'll have a word with Linx about this.
我得跟 Linx 说说这个情况
(GROWLING)
(MEN LAUGHING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
IRONGRON: Linx? Linx, you mongrel!
Linx? Linx 你个杂种
I have a bone to pick with you. Come here!
我得跟你理论理论，过来！
I am occupied, Irongron.
我正忙，Irongron
What! Out this minute or I'll burst the door down.
什么？过了这会儿我可就把门砸碎了啊
Well? What is it you need to say to me?
怎么？你有什么要同我说的？
Didn't I tell you you might not find my face pleasing?
我有没有告诉过你，你可能会不太喜欢我的相貌
Aye, and never was truer word spoken.
是，再也没有比这更实在的话了
Are they all so fair of face beyond the stars?
星星上面的人都是这样的相貌吗
The variety of sentient life forms is infinite.
智慧生命的形式是无限的
Do you think your primitive features are pleasing to me?
就你们这原始生命的相貌，你觉得我会喜欢吗？
-Well, what is it you want?
-That accursed iron warrior of yours.
- 好了，你想要什么 - 你那个下了咒语的铁武士
You are pleased with it?
你还满意吗？
Some knave with a crossbow shot the control from my hand.
某个拿十字弓的混蛋从我手上把控制器射掉了
The iron man became crazed, tried to kill all of us.
那个铁人就疯了，要杀了我们所有人
Perhaps the hand control unit itself is a weakness.
也许手持控制器本身就是个弱点
I will make you a better warrior, Irongron.
我会给你造一个更好的武士，Irongron
One that'll obey your voice perhaps.
一个服从你的声音的，或许
First, help me kill the one I have now.
It still struggles to slay my knaves.
首先，帮我杀了我已经有的那个，它还在追杀我的那些混球呢
It cannot be killed. It was never alive.
不可能杀死它，它从来也不是活的
Come, I will de-activate it.
来，我来关闭它
Professor Morrison?
莫瑞森教授？
Professor.
教授
Absolute lunacy.
完全精神错乱了
- Rubeish!
- What? Who is it?
- Rubeish！- 啥？谁啊？
It's me. It's the Doctor. Don't you remember?
是我，博士。还记得我吗
We were on the same landing at the research centre.
在研究中心时我们在同一楼层啊
Oh, my dear fellow. So he's got you, too, has he?
噢，亲爱的朋友，这么说他把你也抓住了，是吗？
No, hardly. Look, Professor,
what's wrong with all these people?
不，没那么容易。看看，教授，这些人是怎么回事？
Hypnotised. Can't get a word out of them. Rotten company.
都被催眠了，从他们那里一个字也问不出来。都烂掉了
- Well, you seem to be all right.
- Oh, didn't work with me.
- 不过，你好像挺正常 - 哦，对我不起作用
- Strong-minded, you see.
- Yes, and very nearly blind.
- 意志力很强的，你看  - 是的，而且很盲
Oh, nonsense.
噢，胡说
Obviously working some sort of ocular device.
显然是某种视觉屏蔽装置
Professor, have you any idea where you are?
教授，对于你现在在哪儿你有概念吗？
Some medieval English castle, I suspect.
某座中世纪英国城堡吧，我怀疑
I've been feeling the carvings on some of these columns.
我是从这些柱子上的雕刻来揣测的
They're astonishingly well preserved.
它们保存得异常地完好
Yes, you're in a castle all right,
but do you know the time?
是的，你的确是在一座城堡里，但你知道时间吗？
About four in the afternoon.
We haven't had breakfast yet, you know.
大约下午四点。我们连早饭还没吃呢，你看
Doesn't feed us much. Once a day if we're lucky.
很少给我们提供食物，运气好的话一天有一顿
Now, Professor, listen to me.
现在，教授，请听我说
This may come as a shock to you so steel yourself.
这可能会吓着你，所以做好心理准备
You have been brought back
to the early years of the Middle Ages.
你们被带回到了中世纪的早期
That's interesting.
这很有意思
I've always maintained that the Loop Theory of Time
我一直就觉得＜时间循环理论＞
shouldn't have been so arrogantly dismissed
by Crabshaw and his cronies.
不应该被 Crabshaw 那帮人轻易地否定了
Tell me about it some other time.
回头再讨论这个吧
We've got to get out of here before Linx comes back.
我们得在 Linx 回来之前逃离这个地方
Not yet, Doctor. This is the opportunity of a lifetime.
先别，博士，这可是一生中难得的机会啊
There's some most interesting work being done here.
这里还有很多非常有意思的成果
If only I could see it all properly.
最好我能把它们都研究明白
Professor, your life is in considerable danger.
I must insist you...
教授，你的性命处于相当大的危险之中，我坚持要你...
You go if you want to, Doctor. Go on, but leave me alone.
你要走就走吧，博士，不过不要管我
- Professor, don't you understand?
- Stop!
- 教授，你不明白吗？
- 停下！
- You are the one called the Doctor?
- You know who I am?
- 你就是那个叫做博士的？ - 你知道我是谁？
I have been expecting you. Why did you follow me to this time?
我一直在等着你呢，为什么跟我跟到这个时代来？
To prevent your interference with the affairs of Earth.
为了阻止你干涉地球事物
Don't you realise the harm that you'll cause?
你没有意识到你所造成的伤害吗？
This primitive planet and its affairs are of no importance.
这个原始星期的事情没什么重要的
That's a typically Sontaran attitude.
这是典型的桑塔人态度
Only one thing matters, to complete the repairs to my ship
我唯一在乎的事情，是完成我飞船的修理
and return to the glorious war that is my destiny.
返回到光荣的战斗中去，那才是我的归宿
Nothing must interfere with that, nothing and nobody.
没什么能干涉这个，没什么能，也没谁能
I vouch for her, my lord.
Without her help, I would not be here.
我为她担保，大人。没有她帮忙，我不能回到这里
She looks like one I would trust.
她看起来像是我能信任的人
Sit, child. Tell us where you're from.
坐下，孩子，告诉我们你从哪里来的
I can't. It's too difficult to explain.
我没法说，这太难解释了
The manner of her dress is strange,
and the manner of her speech.
她的穿着风格很奇怪，说话风格也是
There is much strange at Irongron's castle, Sir Edward.
Irongron 城堡里也有很多奇怪的事情，爱德华爵士
I told you of the knight that fights on
though it should be dead.
我跟你说过吧，那个骑士本来该死了，但还可以战斗
And one of the guards told me
there's a man from the stars that lives among them.
有个守卫还跟我说，有个从星星上来的人跟他们住在一起
A mighty wizard who makes magic weapons.
是个强大的巫师，会制造魔法武器
A man from the stars.
一个从星星来的人
I've heard it said he has the help of devils and magicians.
我听到过传言，说他得到了魔鬼和魔法师的帮助
- It is true, Sir Edward. I have seen it.
- Well, I know who's helping him.
- 这是真的，爱德华爵士，我看到过 - 对了，我知道谁在帮助他了
- It's the Doctor.
- The doctor?
- 是那个博士   - 博士？
Well, that's what he calls himself,
but he's no magician.
哦，他自己说自己叫这个。不过他不是魔法师
- Just some eccentric scientist.
- What does she say?
- 只是个心术不正的科学家 - 她说什么？
The words are strange, but I know her meaning.
用词有点奇怪，但我大概知道她的意思
Who is this doctor? What do you know of him?
这个博士是谁？对于他你都知道些什么？
Scientists, learned men.
科学家，学识渊博的人
They're being taken from the place I come from,
他们被劫持到了这里，从我来的那个地方
and I believe that the Doctor is bringing them here
而且我相信是博士把他们带过来的
and handing them over to Irongron.
把他们交给了 Irongron
What would Irongron want with these wizards?
Irongron 想要这些巫师干什么？
To make him magic weapons, my lady.
给他制造魔法武器，夫人
Irongron thinks only of war and conquest.
Irongron 脑子里只有战斗和征服
Anything that makes Irongron strong can work only to our harm.
任何能让 Irongron 强大的东西，都能给我们带来伤害
With an army of magic knights such as I fought,
就我斗过的那种魔法骑士，要是有了一整支军队
Irongron could conquer the whole kingdom.
Irongron 可以征服整个王国了
Who knows what other sorceries
he may soon have at his command?
谁知道还会有什么别的魔法师会听命于他
I'm sure the Doctor's the key to it all.
我相信博士是这一切的关键
He was there when one of the scientists was taken.
其中一个科学家被劫走的时候他就在现场
He has a machine that can travel through time.
他有一台可以穿越时间的机器
Well, it must be him, and somehow we've got to stop him.
嗯，肯定是他，我们得用个什么法子阻止他
If he's Irongron's ally,
如果他是 Irongron 的同伙
he sits safe within Irongron's walls.
There's nought we can do.
他稳稳地坐在 Irongron 的城墙内，我们拿他没办法
Oh, there's always something you can do.
It's just a matter of working out what.
噢，总是会有办法的，只是具体什么办法的问题
- A brave speech.
- She has the heart of a lion, sire.
- 这话很勇敢 - 她有一颗狮子一般的心，大人
I saw her give Irongron the sharp edge of her tongue.
我看见过他跟 Irongron 唇枪舌战
If I had an army of girls such as you,
I might hold this castle forever.
如果我有一队像你这样的女孩儿，我可能就可以永远守住这座城堡了
As it is, how can I fight Irongron and this doctor?
就目前来说，我怎么才能打得过 Irongron 和这个博士呢？
All right, I'll tell you how.
好吧，我来告诉你怎么弄
Now, the first thing we must do is grab the Doctor
现在，我们必须做的第一件事是抓住博士
and get him away from Irongron.
把他从 Irongron 那里弄走
And force him to make his magic for me? Aha, good thought.
然后强迫让他的魔法为我效力？啊哈，好想法
Aye, but how could it be done?
是啊，不过怎样才能搞定呢？
Oh, what's wrong with you?
All it needs is a sort of commando raid.
噢，你们怎么回事？只需要一个突击小队什么的就行了啊
You knock out the sentries, rush into the castle,
把哨兵敲晕，冲进城堡
grab the Doctor, and away.
抓住博士，然后走人
- You've got soldiers, haven't you?
- A handful.
- 你手头有士兵吧，有吗
- 有几个
- A raid? A bold plan.
- I'll go, Sir Edward.
- 一个小队？这计划很大胆
- 我去，爱德华爵士
You resisted well, Doctor.
你抵抗力不错，博士
I could have increased the power,
but I might have killed you.
我本可以加大功率的，但可能会杀死你
I need you alive.
我需要你活着
A brain of your capacity can be of use to me.
你这样容量的脑子对我来说很有用
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're not of this planet. How came you to be here?
你不是这个星球上的，怎么来到这里的？
Oh, I'm just a tourist. I like it here.
哦，我只是一个游客，我喜欢这里
- This hole in space?
- You haven't seen it at its best.
- 就这个破地方？ - 你没有见到它最好的一面
It has no military value, no strategic significance.
它没有军事价值，没有战略重要性
Once again, a Sontaran philosophy.
又一次，桑塔人的哲学
I'm Commander Linx, Fifth Sontaran Army Space Fleet.
我是军官 Linx，第五桑塔陆军太空舰队
Ah, yes. Yes, as I thought.
啊，是的是的，一如我所料
A Sontaran warrior.
一位桑塔战士
So, the perpetual war between the Sontarans and the Rutans
这么说，桑塔人和如坦人的持久战
- has spread to this tiny planet, has it?
- Emergency landing.
- 已经扩大到这个小星球了，是吗？
- 紧急降落而已
I was on a reconnaissance mission
when I was attacked
我在一次勘测任务中被袭击了
by a squadron of Rutan fighters.
对方是一中队的如坦战士
You have encountered my race before, Doctor?
你以前碰见过我的族人，博士？
Unfortunately.
很不幸，是的
I'll overlook that insult for the moment.
我暂且忽略你这种侮辱
- What is your native planet?
- Gallifrey. I am a Time Lord.
- 你的母星是哪个？ - 咖喱弗瑞，我是个时间领主
Ah, yes.
啊，是了
A race of great technical achievement,
一个有很高技术成就的种族
but lacking the morale to withstand a determined assault.
但缺乏士气, 无法承受坚决的攻击
- Oh, you think so?
- I'm only a lowly commander, Doctor.
- 哦，你这么想？ - 我只是个低层军官，博士
I merely quote from the appreciation
circulated by our military intelligence.
我只不过是引用我们军队情报部门散发的评价
Well, you'd be well advised
好吧，我倒是强烈建议你
never to put that appreciation to the test, Linx.
永远不会去验证那些评价，Linx
My only ambition at the moment is to return to my squadron.
在这一刻我唯一的夙愿，是返回我的中队
You can be of value to me. You can help repair this ship.
你对我来说是有价值的，可以帮忙维修飞船
You seem to have acquired some help already.
你似乎已经获得了一些帮助
Primitives. I adapted my ship's frequency modulator
很有限。我改造了飞船的频率调制器
and projected myself forward as far as I could.
尽力将我延时间线向前投射
Unfortunately, I only had the power
to reach the 20th century.
不幸的是，我的功率只够我到达20世纪
From which you stole the equipment
你从那里偷了这些设备
and the skilled help that you couldn't find here.
还有那些你从这里找不到的技术援助
Yes.
是的
But the work goes slowly.
但工作进展很慢
Commander Linx, if you will return
these people to their own time,
指挥官 Linx，如果你愿意将这些人送回他们原来的时间
I might possibly consider helping you.
我或许可以考虑帮你
Do not attempt to bargain with me, Doctor!
别试图和我讲条件，博士
Take that seat there by the controls.
去控制开关那边坐着
Move.
走
You're interfering with human evolution, Linx.
你在干涉人类进化史，Linx
Don't you realise the damage
that you're going to do to them?
你没有意识到你会对他们造成的伤害吗？
I have no interest in human evolution.
我对人类进化没有兴趣
I'm placing you under auto-control, Doctor,
我要将你放置于自动控制之下，博士
to ensure your complete cooperation.
以确保你会完全合作
Human beings must be allowed
to develop at their own pace.
人类必须要让他们以自己的步伐演进
At this period, they're just a few steps away from barbarism.
在这个阶段，他们刚刚脱离野蛮状态，还没走几步
You will monitor progress rates on
the input panel against the programmer.
你得在这个输入面板上监控程序员的进度
Now I must leave you in charge for a time.
现在我必须得让你自己负责一段时间了
You give them breech-loading guns now,
你现在就给他们致命的枪械
they'll have atomic weapons by the 17th century.
他们不到17世纪就会有原子武器了
They'll have the capability to destroy their own planet
然后他们就有了能摧毁他们星球的能力
before they're civilised enough to handle it!
但他们的文明还不能处理这类事情
You would do well to concentrate
on the task I have given you, Doctor.
你要是聚焦在我给你的任务上的话，还是能做好的，博士
Answer the programmer.
回应程序员
I still say this is no work for women.
我仍然认为这不是女人干的事情
I wouldn't have missed this for anything.
我不想错过这里任何一件事
Anyway, I'm the only one who knows
what the Doctor looks like.
不管怎么说，我是唯一知道博士长什么样子的
Come on, this way.
快来，这边
Ah, now these are more to my taste
than your iron man, Linx.
啊，比起铁人来这些更对我的口味，Linx
I will still perfect the fighting robot
for your army, Irongron.
我还在为你的军队完善战斗机器人，Irongron
We'll take these weapons to the men, Bloodaxe,
把这些武器散发下去，Bloodaxe
and I shall instruct them in their use.
我会教他们怎么使用
Rubeish! Professor, over here quickly.
Rubeish! 教授，快过来
Is that you, Doctor? I thought you were going.
是你吗，博士？我以为你已经走了
- A change of plan. I want your help.
- Are you wearing a hat?
- 计划有变，我需要你的帮助
- 你戴的是一顶帽子吗？
Behind me you'll find a panel. There's a switch on it.
在我身后你能找到一个面板，上面有个开关
It's dangerous, overheats the brain.
这很危险，可能烧坏你的脑子
- Panel... Oh, yes, I've got it.
- Right, turn the switch.
- 面板...噢，是有，我找到了  - 好，扳动开关
I've always thought that's why judges are so peculiar.
我一直在想为什么法官都如此特别
It's those wigs they wear.
原来是他们所戴的假发
No! No! That's the wrong... No, no, man!
不，错了！不是那个... 不，不，伙计
Sorry. I do wish I'd brought my glasses.
抱歉，我真期望我把眼镜也带过来了
Yes, so do I. It was the wrong one.
是，我也期望。刚才搞错了
Is this the one?
这个对了吗？
Yes, that was the one.
Thank you very much indeed, Professor.
是的，就是这个。真的非常谢谢你，教授
- Not at all, Smith.
- Smith. Yes, of course.
- 不用谢，史密斯 - 史密斯？是了，当然是
Will you excuse me? I've got to go and find a young girl.
我现告辞了，我必须得走了，得去找一个年轻女孩儿
I'll see you later, I hope.
回头再见，我期望
Young girl? I should've thought
he was a bit old for that sort of thing.
年轻女孩儿？我原本以为他有点太老了，不适合那类事情
Oh, well.
噢，好吧
Ah, good evening.
啊，晚上好
Get after him! Call the guards!
去追他！叫守卫！
(SHOUTING)
Catch him!
抓住他！
(SHOUTING)
Grab him! Grab him!
抓住他，抓住他！
(SHOUTING)
He who strikes Irongron dies!
敢犯我 Irongron 者死！